The Trench is a war, history film directed by William Boyd.
The Trench tells the story of a group of young British soldiers on the eve of the Battle of
the Somme in the summer of 1916, the worst defeat in British military history.
Against this ill-fated backdrop, the movie depicts the soldiers' experience as a mixture of
boredom, fear, panic, and restlessness, confined to a trench on the front lines.
Sgt. Telford Winter, played by Daniel Craig.
Lance Cpl. Victor Dell, played by Danny Dyer.
Pte. Colin Daventry, played by James D'Arcy.
Pte. Billy Macfarlane, played by Paul Nicholls.
2nd Lt. Ellis Harte, played by Julian Rhind-Tutt.
Pte. Charlie Ambrose, played by Ciarán McMenamin.
The Trench is a 1999 war film written and directed by William
Boyd and starring Paul Nicholls and Daniel Craig.
It depicts the experiences of a group of young British soldiers in the
48 hours leading up to the Battle of the Somme in 1916.
James D'Arcy, Cillian Murphy and Ben Whishaw also appear.
The film explores themes of friendship, world war i,
bravery, trauma, based on true story.